A Guide to the John H. Knowles Papers FA047
Rockefeller Archive Center
John H. Knowles papers
1944-1980, bulk 1960-1979
Rockefeller Archive Center
Knowles, John H.
Rockefeller Foundation
FA047
50.17 Cubic Feet 118 document cases
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted are noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement note
The John H. Knowles papers are divided into six series:
Series 1 - Early Career
Series 2 - Massachusetts General Hospital
Series 3 - Interim
Series 4 - The Rockefeller Foundation
Series 5 - Miscellaneous
Series 1049 - Photographs
Original order has been maintained as far as possible.
Biographical/Historical note
Physician, medical administrator, author, and president of The Rockefeller Foundation. John Hilton Knowles was born May 23, 1926, in Chicago, Illinois, the son of James and Jean Trumbull Knowles. Dr. Knowles received his A.B. from Harvard College (1947) and his M.D. from Washington University School of Medicine (1951). On June 13, 1953, he married Edith M. LaCroix; they had six children.
Dr. Knowles began his medical career in 1951 when he was appointed intern at Massachusetts General Hospital. From 1953-1955 he served as Officer-in-Charge of the Cardiopulmonary Laboratory at Portsmouth Naval Hospital in Portsmouth, Virginia. He returned to Massachusetts General Hospital as a resident, specializing in diseases of the heart and lungs, leaving a year later to do postdoctoral work with the United States Public Health Service at the Universities of Rochester and Buffalo. In 1958 he became Chief Resident in Internal Medicine at Massachusetts General Hospital. The following year he was named Chief of the Pulmonary Disease Unit.
In 1962, Dr. Knowles was appointed General Director of Massachusetts General Hospital, the youngest director in the hospital's history. During the next ten years he upgraded working conditions and wages of the hospital staff, established a medical station at Logan International Airport that was connected to the hospital via television, approved the creation of nine intensive-care units including one for the diagnosis and care of cancer patients, and won better rates for hospitals from Blue Cross. He developed a strong interest in social issues of medicine and supported comprehensive federal health insurance and advocated preventive medicine. He was one of a team of doctors sent to Vietnam by President Johnson in 1967 to review and make recommendations concerning the health of the civilian population. In 1969 President Nixon nominated him for the post of Assistant Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare. The nomination was withdrawn six months later because of violent conservative opposition led by Senator Everett Dirkson and the American Medical Association. Prior to leaving Massachusetts General Hospital, Dr. Knowles was censured by the Massachusetts Medical Society for writing an article asserting that many physicians charged exorbitant fees and performed unnecessary operations.
Dr. Knowles left Massachusetts General Hospital in December 1971 and assumed the presidency of The Rockefeller Foundation in July 1972. Among his activities as Foundation president, he established an international relations program to focus on common global problems and set up the Foundation's publishing division to distribute reports on various Foundation-funded conferences. Dr. Knowles also remained active in the field of medicine; New York University Medical Center appointed him professor of medicine. He was a member of Nelson A. Rockefeller's Commission for Critical Choices (1974), editing the commission's final report "Doing Better and Feeling Worse." In 1975 he visited China with the National Committee on United States-China Relations, Inc., a group of "key United States leaders of world affairs," for a first-hand experience of China.
Dr. Knowles died of cancer on March 6, 1979.
A prolific writer and speaker, Dr. Knowles had over 60 articles and 4 books to his credit, including "Vietnam: Medicine and Politics," "Doing Better and Feeling Worse," and "Respiratory Physiology and its Clinical Application," a textbook still used by medical students. He also left two incomplete manuscripts: "Dr. Knowles' Journal" describing the HEW appointment controversy, and "Essays on Medicine and Health."
For a full list of activities, organizations, and honors, see "Who's Who in America," 40th edition, volume 1, 1978-1979, p. 1812, and the RAC biography file.
Scope and Contents note
The John H. Knowles papers consist of professional and personal correspondence, reports, manuscripts, scrapbooks, appointment calendars, information files, photographs, slides, tapes, and a film relating to his administrative posts at Massachusetts General Hospital and The Rockefeller Foundation, and to his medical career. Most of the papers date from his tenure at Massachusetts General Hospital. There is very little concerning The Rockefeller Foundation or his personal life.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 2A 27
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Edith L. Knowles donated the papers of John H. Knowles to the Rockefeller Archive Center in 1980.
Vietnam; China; Medical research; Medical education
- Early Career, 1944-1959; 1; 1.3 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of correspondence, class notes, research notes, and manuscripts relating to Knowles's undergraduate and graduate training, and to his research in diseases of the heart and lungs at Portsmouth Naval Hospital, as a United States Public Health Service fellow, and as intern and resident at Massachusetts General Hospital.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged by subject and chronologically within each subject.
  - Correspondence, 1944-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Harvard - Class Notes (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Harvard - Class Notes, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Washington University - Class Notes, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Washington University - Class Notes, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Washington University - Class Notes, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Washington University - Class Notes, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Washington University - Class Notes, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital - Internship and Residency, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital - Internship and Residency, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital - Lecture Notes, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Portsmouth Hospital - Correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Portsmouth Hospital - Case Histories, 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital - Respiratory Physiology Laboratory, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - U. S. Public Health Service Post - Doctorate Fellow - Non-Respiratory Notes, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - National Academy of Science - Handbook of Biological Data - Lung Volume, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Note Cards, circa 1958 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Note Cards, circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Note Cards, circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Note Cards, circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Note Cards, circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Note Cards, circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Manuscripts - "Alterations in the Valsalva Maneuver Induced by Pulmonary Congestion", 1955 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Manuscripts - "Clinical Test for Pulmonary Congestion with Use of the Valsalva Maneuver", 1956 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Manuscripts - "The Clinical Value of the Valsalva Maneuver in the Detection of Pulmonary Congestion", 1955 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Manuscripts - "Effects of Pleural Talc Poudrage on Pulmonary Function", 1957 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Manuscripts - "Effects on Thoracotomy Pulmonary Function", 1957 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Manuscripts - "Idiopathic Alveolar Hypoventilation", 1956 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Manuscripts - "Possible Errors Using Esophageal Balloon in Determination of Pressure-Volume Characteristics of the Lung and Thoracic Cage", 1959 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Manuscripts - "Pulmonary Function - A Brief Review", 1956 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Manuscripts - "A Simple Clinical Test for the Detection of Pulmonary Congestion Utilizing the Valsalva Maneuver", 1955 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Manuscripts - Unidentified (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Manuscripts - "The Valsalva Maneuver as a Test of Cardiac Function", 1957 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Massachusetts General Hospital, 1947-1972 1959-1971; 2; 22.6 Cubic Feet
  Series 2 contains papers documenting Knowles's professional and personal activities during his tenure at Massachusetts General Hospital, 1959-1971.
  This series is divided into 6 subseries:
  Subseries A - Massachusetts General Hospital
  Subseries B - Professional
  Subseries C - Personal
  Subseries D - Manuscripts
  Subseries E - Printed Material
  Subseries F - Information Files
  - Massachusetts General Hospital, A
    Subseries A concerns Knowles's career at Massachusetts General Hospital, first as chief of the Pulmonary Unit and later as General Director. Types of material in this subseries include correspondence, reports, minutes, and newsletters. Subjects include staff appointments, committee meetings, administrative philosophy, MGH fellows, and the MGH medical unit at Logan Airport.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject, and chronologically within each subject.
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Austin, Dr. W. Gerald, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Barr, Dr. Joseph, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Chief of Surgery, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Cope, Dr. Oliver, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Crawford, Dr. John, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Dental Medicine, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Gross, Dr. Jerome, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Isselbacher, Dr. Kurt J., 1961, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Knowles, Dr. John H., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Medicine, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Medicine, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Medicine, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Nikaido, Dr., 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Orthopedic Surgery, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Pediatrics, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Pope, Dr. Alfred, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Promotions and Reappointments, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Psychiatry, September 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Psychiatry, September 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Psychiatry, September 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Psychiatry, 1963-May 1964 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Psychiatry, Supplemental Material (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Robinson, Dr. James D., 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Scott, Dr. Jesse, 1960, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Swartz, Dr. Morton N., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Sweet, Dr. William H., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Teaching and Education, 1962-1963, 1965, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Ad Hoc Committee - Teaching and Education, 1962-1963, 1965, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Administrative Directives, 1961-1967 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Administrative Function, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Admissions Policy - Teaching Function Questionnaire, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Allen, Dr. Scott I., 1963 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Amino Acid Sequencer, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Animal Farm Committee, 1961-1963 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Annual Reports, 1966, 1968, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Annual Report of 1962 - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Annual Report of 1963 - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Appointment as Director, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Appointment as Director - Congratulations, 1961-1962, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Appointment as Director - Congratulations, 1961-1962, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Appointment as Director - Congratulations, 1961-1962, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Appointment as Director - Articles, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Archives, 1962, 1964-1968 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Balance Study of Hospital Activities, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Barnett, Dr. G. Octo - Computer System, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Barnett, Dr. G. Octo - Computer System, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Barr, Dr. Joseph S., 1961-1963, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Bauer, Dr. Walter, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Bauer, Dr. Walter, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Bay State Rehabilitation Clinic, 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Behavioral Science in Medical Study, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - Berry, Dr. George P. (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Blue Cross Contract, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - Board of Trustees, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Charter and Studies, 1950, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Chief of Units Meetings, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - Committee on Cancer, Heart and Stroke (Box 9, Folder 90)
    - Committee on Research, 1961-1966 (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - Committee on Research, 1961-1966 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - Committee on Research, 1961-1966 (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - Committee on Research - Pilot Study for National Institutes of Health (NIH), 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 94)
    - DeFriez, Dr. Albert I. C., 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 95)
    - Degan, Joseph, 1962-1968 (Box 9, Folder 96)
    - Executive Committee, 1962, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - Expenses, 1962-1964, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - Eye Bank, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - Fees of Hospital-Based Physicians, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Fellowship Applications, 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 101)
    - Fellows - Glazier, Jon B., 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - Fellows - McCormack, Regina, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 103)
    - Fellows - Norman, Joe R., 1959-1964 (Box 9, Folder 104)
    - Fellows - Salazar, Eduardo, 1960, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - Fellows - Schweppe, H. Irving, Jr., 1959-1961, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - Fellows - Stevens, Paul N., 1960-1966 (Box 10, Folder 107)
    - Fellows - Terplan, Martin, 1959-1964 (Box 10, Folder 108)
    - Grant Applications (Not Approved), 1962 (Box 10, Folder 109)
    - Grant Applications, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 110)
    - Grommers, Dr. Frances, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 111)
    - History (Box 10, Folder 112)
    - Horenstein, Dr. Betty, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    - Hospital Function Lectures, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 114)
    - Hospital Improvements, 1952, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 115)
    - Hospital Laundry Association, Inc., 1962-1963, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 116)
    - Hospital Rate Hearings, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 117)
    - House Pupils' Alumni Association, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 118)
    - Inaugural Address, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 119)
    - Internships, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 120)
    - Job Inquiries, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 121)
    - Jerne, Dr. Niels, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 122)
    - Labor Problems, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - Labor Unions, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - "Ladies Home Journal" - "America's 10 Best Hospitals" - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - Lindsay, Dr. John R., 1962-1965 (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - Logan International Airport - Medical Unit Reports, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 127)
    - Mathematics and Medicine Advisory Committee, 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - McDonald, Eleanor - Tumor Registry, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 129)
    - Medical Fees - Collecting, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 129A)
    - Medical Executive Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 131)
    - New York Hospital, 1962, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 132)
    - "News", 1961, 1963-1967 (Box 11, Folder 133)
    - North Shore Council of Hospitals, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 134)
    - Nursing - Ruth Sleeper's Successor, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 134A)
    - Obstetrical Service Committee, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 135)
    - Organization, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 136)
    - Organizational Study, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 137)
    - Organizational Study, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 138)
    - Ovulation Control Clinic, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 139)
    - Payroll, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 140)
    - Pediatric Services, March 1964-1965, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 141)
    - Pediatric Services, 1961-February 1964 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    - Pediatric Services, 1961-February 1964 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - "A Personalized View of the History of the MGH Research Committee" by Paul Zamecnik (Box 12, Folder 144)
    - Position Appointment Form (Box 12, Folder 145)
    - Preventive Medicine, 1947, 1952, 1961-1964 (Box 12, Folder 146)
    - "Progress and Planning at MGH", 1969 (Box 12, Folder 147)
    - Questionnaires and Inquiries, 1962-1967 (Box 12, Folder 148)
    - Radiotherapy Planning Report, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 149)
    - Reimbursement for In-House Patients, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 150)
    - Reimbursement for In-House Patients, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 151)
    - Reimbursement for In-House Patients, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 152)
    - Reimbursement for In-House Patients, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 153)
    - Reimbursement for In-House Patients, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 154)
    - Reimbursement for In-House Patients - Commissioner John J. McCarthy, September 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 155)
    - Reimbursement for In-House Patients - Commissioner John J. McCarthy, January-August 1965 (Box 14, Folder 156)
    - Research Memos, 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 157)
    - Research Society (Box 14, Folder 158)
    - Respiratory Unit, 1962-1964, 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 159)
    - Sagamore Foundation, 1962, 1964-1968 (Box 14, Folder 160)
    - School of Medical Illustration, 1961-1966 (Box 14, Folder 161)
    - Selective Service, 1961-1965 (Box 14, Folder 162)
    - Seven Year Report, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 163)
    - Seven Year Report, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 164)
    - Sidel, Dr. Victor W., October 1964-1966 (Box 14, Folder 165)
    - Sidel, Dr. Victor W., October 1964-1966 (Box 14, Folder 166)
    - Sidel, Dr. Victor W., 1963-September 1964 (Box 15, Folder 167)
    - Soutter, Dr. Lamar, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 168)
    - Staff - Circular Letters, 1962-1968 (Box 15, Folder 169)
    - Staff - Circular Letters, 1962-1968 (Box 15, Folder 170)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 15, Folder 171)
    - Staff Correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 15, Folder 172)
    - Staff Organization, 1950-1961 (Box 15, Folder 173)
    - Teamster's Local 380, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 174)
    - Telephones, 1963-1965 (Box 15, Folder 175)
    - Trustees (Box 15, Folder 176)
    - U. S. Government Health Bills, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 177)
    - U. S. Government Health Bills, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 178)
    - "U. S. S. Boston" (Box 16, Folder 179)
    - Utilization Review Committee - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 16, Folder 180)
    - Utilization Review Committee - Minutes, October 4, 1966-October 1967 (Box 16, Folder 181)
    - Utilization Review Committee - Minutes, October 4, 1966-October 1967 (Box 16, Folder 182)
    - Utilization Review Committee - Minutes, October 4, 1966-October 1967 (Box 16, Folder 183)
    - Utilization Review Committee - Minutes, June 17-September 27, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 184)
    - Utilization Review Committee - Minutes, June 17-September 27, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 185)
    - Utilization Review Committee - Supplemental Material (Box 17, Folder 186)
    - Visiting Committee of the Child Psychiatry Unit, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 187)
    - West, Dr. John B., 1961-1964 (Box 17, Folder 188)
    - Westinghouse Broadcasting Company, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 189)
    - "The World of MGH", 1962-1967 (Box 17, Folder 190)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital - Professional, B
    Subseries B documents Knowles's professional interests and activities, through correspondence, reports, and lecture notes. Subjects include speaking engagements, congressional testimony on medical costs and government health insurance, the 1967 trip to Vietnam, the 1969 proposed appointment as assistant secretary of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, chapters for Harrison's Textbook of medicine, teaching lectures at Harvard, regional planning, and work with Boston City Hospital, McLean Hospital, and various New York City hospitals.
    - Action for Boston Community Development, Inc., 1963-1965 (Box 17, Folder 191)
    - Advisory Committee for Statewide Planning for Vocational Rehabilitation Services, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 192)
    - Advisory Committee on Medical Care Administration Program - Boston University, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 193)
    - Aesculapian Club, 1960-1962, 1964, 1966-1967 (Box 17, Folder 194)
    - Alpha Omega Alpha, Lexington, Kentucky Chapter - Annual Lecture, 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 195)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1965-1968 (Box 17, Folder 196)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Bi-Centennial Planning Committee, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 197)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 198)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science - Committee on Scientific Freedom and Responsibility, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 199)
    - American Board of Internal Medicine, 1958-1959 (Box 18, Folder 200)
    - American Cancer Society, Inc., 1962 (Box 18, Folder 201)
    - American Clinical and Climatological Society Association, 1964-1970 (Box 18, Folder 202)
    - American College of Physicians, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 203)
    - American College of Physicians - Downstate New York Region Meeting, 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 204)
    - American College of Physicians - Socioeconomic Aspects of Medicine Panel, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 205)
    - American Federation for Clinical Research, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 206)
    - American Heart Association, Inc., 1960 (Box 18, Folder 207)
    - American Hospital Association (Box 18, Folder 208)
    - American Hospital Association - Committee on American Hospital Association Program - Report, 1965-1967 (Box 18, Folder 208A)
    - American Hospital Association - Committee on Physicians, 1970-1971 (Box 18A, Folder 209)
    - American Hospital Association - Committee on Physicians, 1970-1971 (Box 18A, Folder 210)
    - American Hospital Association - Committee on Physicians - Chicago Meeting, 1970-1971 (Box 18A, Folder 211)
    - American Medical Association, 1968-1970 (Box 18A, Folder 212)
    - American Medical Association - Committee on Research and Planning, 1967-1969 (Box 18A, Folder 213)
    - American Medical Association - Pulmonary Function Exhibit, 1961 (Box 18A, Folder 214)
    - American Hospital Association - Committee on Physicians, 1970-1971 (Box 18A, Folder 209)
    - American Hospital Association - Committee on Physicians, 1970-1971 (Box 18A, Folder 210)
    - American Hospital Association - Committee on Physicians - Chicago Meeting, 1970-1971 (Box 18A, Folder 211)
    - American Medical Association, 1968-1970 (Box 18A, Folder 212)
    - American Medical Association - Committee on Research and Planning, 1967-1969 (Box 18A, Folder 213)
    - American Medical Association - Pulmonary Function Exhibit, 1961 (Box 18A, Folder 214)
    - American Nurses' Association, Inc., 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 215)
    - American Physiological Society, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 216)
    - American Psychiatric Association, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 217)
    - American Public Health Association, Inc., 1962 (Box 19, Folder 218)
    - American Review of Respiratory Diseases, 1960-1961 (Box 19, Folder 219)
    - American Sociological Association (Box 19, Folder 220)
    - American Thoracic Society (Box 19, Folder 221)
    - Anti-War Materials (Box 19, Folder 222)
    - Associated Harvard Alumni - Committee on Nominations, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 223)